i don't know about you but when i think
of some of the most helpful pieces of
equipment you could have for your
workouts a weight bench is right up
there at the top of my list specifically
an adjustable weight bench since they
allow you to work out your entire upper
body the force usa commercial fid bench
might be one of the better commercial
grade options that you could add to your
home gym i've been using mine for a
while so today i'm gonna break down my
findings for y'all
what's up everybody it's jake you know
the deal i'm in the barbing garage gym
with another review ready to go for
y'all this time i've got the force usa
commercial fid bench in this video i'm
going to take you through everything you
need to know about this weight bench
from the price the features you're going
to find of course some pros and cons as
well as who should or maybe should not
add this to their home gym but before i
get going you know we've reviewed a lot
of weight benches on barbin.com and if
you want to browse our best list just go
ahead and search barbind best weight
benches and you can find out for
yourself which ones we like the best
[Music]
okay so what do i like about this weight
bench well for starters it's rated to
hold up to 300 pounds so all my power
lifters out there it's a pretty solid
option for you to consider it's an fid
bench so you can adjust it to do incline
or decline bench presses if you want to
i think it's pretty comfortable thanks
to the foam padding right here and it
does have a handle and some wheels so
you can move it around your gym
plus i really like how force usa throws
a lifetime structural warranty on their
products now that's only going to cover
manufacturing defects but you know
that's still a pretty nice security
blanket added on to this weight bench
okay so what about the cons now with
this weight bench okay so i know i said
you know it is an fid bench you can
technically use this for your decline
bench press but as you can see there's
nowhere for your legs to go nowhere to
keep your body really in place so that
could be a bit of a problem just you
know in terms of getting that traction
and you know being safe while you're
doing a decline bench press there's also
a bit of a gap right here between the
two pads that's pretty common with
adjustable weight benches such as this
one but it's still not fun it's still a
little bit uncomfortable and you got to
deal with this piece of steel right here
on your lower back and like i said
that's just not fun to deal with the pad
right here it's 12 inches wide and you
know that might be fine for somebody
like myself but there's also people out
there that might want a wider back pad
and unfortunately
you just can't add that on to this
weight bench and
listed right around 500
and you don't get any extra attachments
that itself could be a turn off for some
of y'all watching
[Music]
okay so let's dig into the money now
with this weight bench if you head over
to the force usa website you'll find
this weight bench to be listed right
around 450
add-on shipping that's you know another
50 or so so you're looking right around
500 total for this bench
i know that's kind of a lot of money but
overall quality as well as the weight
rating of this bench is really is what's
driving that price
so like i said if you're a power lifter
looking for a solid weight bench this is
a pretty good option for you to consider
and it might be well worth your money
because it is going to be able to hang
in there and handle that heavy weight
that you're pushing but
if you want a weight bench to feature a
leg roller attachment or you know maybe
even a preacher curl attachment you have
to look elsewhere you know force usa
actually does offer a weight bench that
has both of those attachments with your
purchase
but the weight rating of that bench is
nearly half of what this one is so you
know a little bit of pros and cons with
both of them right there good news is
as i mentioned earlier you do have a
lifetime structural warranty on this
weight bench it's going to cover any
manufacturing defects and you can even
finance your purchase through a firm
that's going to split everything up into
around 40 or so per month
okay so let's talk about the build now
with this weight bench i don't know what
gauge steel they use but i gotta say
this is very sturdy it feels just like
something that you're gonna find at a
professional gym so that's nice that you
have that aspect in your home gym it is
rated to hold up to 1300 pounds i
personally love that and i think all
those power lifters out there are gonna
especially love that it's about 17
inches tall around 50 inches long and
including the wheels it's about 28
inches wide you do have seven different
adjustments for the back pad which is 12
inches wide and the seat does have three
different adjustments on its own the
padding here is super comfortable it's
made from foam so i could probably take
a nap on this thing if i wanted to so
that's pretty nice now in terms of
features there's really not a whole lot
that you're working with what you see is
kind of what you get so talking about
adjustments again
if you wanted to put this in the decline
position all you got to do is push
forward on this back post right here and
you're going to unlock that ability
you don't have any extra attachments
which might be a bummer for some of
y'all or you know some of y'all really
might not care about that now in terms
of weight of this bench i'm not really
sure i'm guessing probably around 60 to
65 pounds or so just compared to some
other weight benches that i've used in
the past but you know good news is you
do have a pretty
easy handle to grab down there on that
side as well as some wheels so you can
definitely move this around your home
gym at ease
[Music]
all right y'all i'm gonna give you a
quick walk around this weight bench now
let's start with the padding it's made
from foam so it's pretty comfortable but
also found it to be pretty firm that's a
nice touch a little bit of duality there
i guess you could say now when it comes
to the seat you do have three different
adjustments for you to work with and to
do that all you need to do there's a
handle on both sides right here just
lift up on it and you can as you can see
you can lock it into all
three
spots right there which is pretty nice
now in terms of portability you do have
a handle right here on the front it's
pretty easy to grab nice easy to access
to it which is a nice touch as well and
maybe an underrated feature here is
actually that this front foot right here
doesn't take up a whole lot of space so
you don't have to deal with you know
anything getting in the way of your feet
when you go to get set up for a bench
press
that can be pretty annoying now once
again you do have pretty noticeable gap
right here between the two pads it's a
little bit annoying but you know it's
pretty common with adjustable weight
benches so just something you got to
kind of work with now in terms of
adjusting the back pad you have seven
different adjustments here so let's
slide you down over here
and to do that you know all you have to
do there are handles right here on both
sides but to lift it up you can simply
just lift up on the actual back pad if
you want to and as you can see you got
all these different adjustments for you
to work with now if you wanted to use
this for a decline bench press all you
have to do is push this down right here
lift up on the seat
or the back pad excuse me
lay it down and you're good to go
sometimes this will get a little stuck
on you but you know that's okay it's
part of it you can just move it out of
the way and also you do have your wheels
back here on this side and this little
platform right here can actually double
i guess you could say for your spotter
to stand on during your bench presses
[Music]
okay so who should purchase this weight
bench well
anybody out there looking for a
commercial grade weight bench to add to
their home gym
this is a really good option for you to
consider you know especially if you're a
power lifter and you're really pumping
some iron because once again this can
hold up to 300 pounds y'all it's also
adjustable so anybody looking to hit
their workouts from different angles
you're gonna love that feature and plus
you know it is super sturdy so i think
this could be really the only weight
bench that you need and it could last
you a really long time potentially even
a lifetime
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase this weight bench
okay so while 500
might be a pretty good deal for anybody
who's you know putting the weight limit
of this bench to the test but if you're
not lifting that heavy then you know you
don't need a weight bench that can
handle up to 1300 pounds so i would
suggest you know exploring some other
options that are probably going to be a
little bit cheaper as well
also if you're looking for a weight
bench that comes with extra attachments
you know this one does not have any so
that might be a little bit disappointing
and it's also not compatible with any so
once again i'd explore some other
options and while you definitely can
technically use this for a decline bench
press you don't have anywhere for your
legs for your feet to go so it's going
to be a little difficult in terms of
keeping your body in place so you know
that could be a bit of a problem in
itself and also you know if you're just
not interested in the adjustments of
this weight bench then well i would just
suggest
going and getting a regular old flat
bench you know and that's also going to
save you a couple bucks in the long run
[Music]
okay i know this is y'all's least
favorite part of my videos but it's time
for me to go
if you're a power lifter i think this is
a really solid option for you to
consider because it can handle up to 300
pounds however
if you're not coming close to that much
weight you know i would definitely
recommend
a different option out there for you and
remember you know this weight bench does
not come with any extra attachments and
it might not be the optimal choice for
you to do a decline bench press with
because
there's nowhere for your legs to go and
it's probably going to be a little
difficult just to keep your body in
place
thanks for watching y'all hope this
video was helpful and that i was able to
answer any questions you might have
about this weight bench
stay on the lookout for my next video
but for now head over to barbin.com and
you can read more about this product
just search barbind force usa commercial
fid bench review and you can read
everything i talked about here today
with you all
i'll see y'all next time
[Music]
you